Yashar Aliabbasi

+90 (501) 320 9310 aliabbasi.yashar@gmail.com

I am a .Net backend developer especially interested in building enterprise-grade distributed applications, scaling systems up, and shipping reliable applications. I am an experienced IT professional with a passion for learning and teaching. I oversee technical teams, create accessible development environments, fix technical debt, provide best practice code examples, and mentor developers.

Technologies and Languages

Languages: C#, Javascript, Typescript, ES6

Technologies: MySQL, Postgres, SQL Server, Sqlite, MongoDB, AWS, Git

Libraries & Tools:
 SignalR, Hotchocolate, Hangfire, Quartz.NET, EF Core, Dapper, RabbitMQ, Redis, Azure

Service Bus

DevOps: Docker, TeamCity

Other: Data structures and algorithms, GraphQL, RestFul, Bitbucket, Gitlab, Github, Jira, TDD,

SOLID, Design Patterns, Clean Code

Work Experience

Team Leader Patika Global Sep 2022 - Present Istanbul, Turkey

- Mentoring and orchestrating a team of six back-end developers, two front-end developers, and one DevOps engineer.
- Hired and trained more than six new developers and mentored new hires to ensure success within the team.
- Architected and executed a complete overhaul of database infrastructure, streamlining queries and delivering a
 remarkable 7x decrease in response time. Eliminated 30% of query errors for a service ordering application that
 seamlessly communicates with thousands of Android and iOS apps via the SignalR library.

Senior Software Engineer

Patika Global

2021 - 2022

Istanbul, Turkey

- Converted PHP application into .Net and redesigned using microservice architecture, leading to a **60% increase** in security and **3 times faster performance**, enabling the application to handle four times as many requests.
- Architected and designed an innovative .NET framework, adopted across four enterprise projects; drove a 50% increase in productivity and reduced errors by 30% through the utilization of advanced testing methodologies and optimized development workflows.
- Designed a series of automated tests utilizing tools such as xUnit and Visual Studio, which minimized the time and resources required for manual testing.

Senior Back-end Engineer

Resina Soft

2019 - 2021

Istanbul, Turkey

- Enhanced transaction monitoring by clarifying profit allocation and payment processes in the **LMS** project with the Backend team, resulting in a **40**% reduction in support time.
- The existing application was redesigned to use open-source libraries and libraries that were authored internally instead of licensed libraries, resulting in a **20%** annual savings in budget.
- Produced a seamless migration from **REST APIs** to **GraphQL** architecture, resulting in a remarkable **7-fold** increase in application speed and mitigation of **10** critical security vulnerabilities.

ASP.net core web developer

Shoniz

2015-2019

Tabriz, Iran

- Engineered an advanced application that streamlined the control and monitoring of company devices, leading to a **5-fold** improvement in reaction times. By automating over **fifty** manual processes and integrating key departments, the application aligned with the latest company requirements.
- Formulated approximately **20** manual and spreadsheet-based procedures and integrated them into one central application that resulted in a **70%** reduction in duplication of data entry.
- Improved the existing application so that it could communicate with mobile applications and integrated with **three** other applications.

.Net Windows Form Developer

Takro System

2012-2014

Tabriz, Iran

- Collaborated in the modeling, analysis, and development of accounting applications which improved **thirteen** algorithms based on articles reviewed at the time.
- By modeling and documenting old codes, about **20** query problems were resolved, and their performance was raised by a factor of **30**%.

Education and Certifications

• **B.Sc. Software Engineering,** Payam-e-Noor University, Tabriz.

2006 - 2012